Jinhyuk Yoon

POSTECH, Haptics and Virtual Reality Laboratory

Rooms 011, Science Building 4, 77 Cheongam-Ro, Nam-Gu, Pohang, Gyeongbuk, Korea

jinhyukyoon@postech.ac.kr https://www.jinhyukyoon.com

Feb 2019 - Present

Jan 2019 – Feb 2019

I am an interaction designer, engineer and science communicator building immersive and impressive experience. I love interacting with people and getting inspired through various projects such as research, performance, art work, and education. Through technological and humanistic point of view, I've been trying to create meaningful experience.

Professional Experience

POSTECH, Haptics and Virtual Reality Laboratory

Research Intern

Developing a pneumatic haptic device to provide various tactile experiences.

Samsung Electronics, Digital Appliances Division, Core Component R&D Lab

Mechanical Design Intern

Analyzed mechanical property of spring and damper hinge mounted in oven door. Deployed the analysis result on interactive data platform to simplify design process.

Sovoro Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

Communications Manager

Conducted UI/UX research and design of the service, catalog design, and market research. Engaged in business activity related with public institution, educational institution, and people with hearing loss.

Korea Foundation for the Advancement of Science & Creativity

Science Communicator

Gave talk, performed science street performance, and acted science play only for adults as a finalist of the FameLab Korea and science communicator commissioned by minister of Ministry of Science & ICT.

Asan Medical Center, Biomedical Engineering Research Center

Research Intern

Designed concept prototype of Ankle Rehabilitation Assistant which analyzes ankle torque and provides rehabilitative movement.

Aug 2017 – Sep 2017

May 2016 – Jan 2018

Leadership Experience

POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering

Jan 2016 – Mar 2017

Student President

Directed student membership training, professor appreciation banquet, association program with KAIST and founded basketball and badminton club.

POSTECH, Student Election Committee

Sep 2016 - Nov 2016

Chairman

Organized the student election committee and run the election for central student president.

TEDxPOSTECH Nov 2014 – Nov 2015

Director

Organized TEDx event under the theme 'question' with 6 speakers. Regular application was fully booked in 50 seconds after opening. Conducted team building, speaker and sponsor contact, stage planning and host at the event.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering

2014 - Present

2016 - Present

Pohang University of Science and Technology (POSTECH)

Minor in Industrial management engineering. Expect to graduate with *Magna Cum Laude*

Awards and Honors

National Academic Excellence Scholarship

Korea Student Aid Foundation

| Commission Letter Minister of Ministry of Science & ICT commissioned me as a science communicator | 2016 |
|---|------------|
| Finalist Nationwide Top 11 of the 3 rd FameLab Korea | 2016 |
| Runners up Artience Creation Challenge 30x30 hosted by British Council | 2017 |
| Honorable Mention 3 Minutes Science Speech Contest hosted by POSTECH | 2015 |
| Student of the Year POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering | 2015, 2016 |
| The 4 th Prize The 2 nd POSTECH Hackathon | 2016 |

KT&G Foundation Scholarship

POSTECH

Jigok Scholarship

POSTECH

2014 - 2016

2016

Skills and Tools

Programming Language

C, C++, JAVA, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MATLAB

Graphic Design

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, After Effects, InDesign

3D Design & Analysis

Solidworks, NX

Selected Talks

| Keynote Speech, "About Experience", POSTECH Alumni Conference for Freshman, Pohang | 2018 |
|--|------|
| Keynote Speech, "Engineering and Science Communication", The 5th Integrated Science Leading Teacher Training, Yeongcheon | 2016 |
| Keynote Speech, "About Science Communication", National Youth Science Exploration Competition, Gyeongju | 2016 |
| Talk, "Regain the lost life", Suseong-gu Gosan Library, Daegu | 2018 |
| Talk, "Regain the lost life", KIST Science Station, Seoul | 2017 |
| Talk, "Space food", The 13th Bohyeonsan Starlight Festival, Yeongcheon | 2016 |
| Talk, "Science, Engineering and Me", Seongji Highschool, Yongin | 2017 |
| Talk, "Communicate with Science", Mulgeum High School, Yangsan | 2017 |
| Talk, "Talk with Odd Engineering Student", Samsung Girl's High School, Busan | 2017 |